In this video, I will walk you through on how
to create a data product from scratch.
Also using templates.
For this, we will go to your settings,
to your personal instance, which is also my storage.
Here you can see the team instance,
but we will want to create one locally,
therefore we create one.
I will call this Lego legal
and I added locally here.
Then we can see the data product,
which has been newly created.
First I wanna create a new branch,
which I do here.
I will just do it with a current date.
I create one, as you can see here, it has been created
and it's visible in here.
The first thing I will do is add a work graph, workspace,
pointer, so it's easier to work with
and then it should be visible up here.
Lego. I will
first create a trait called
inventory Inventory set.
I will add a property, which is called quantity.
It's mandatory that is there
and it is numeric one,
which is greater equal two zero.
I'll add this one and it does appear up here.
Now I want to create a type, A type
that is called inventory itself.
The inventory should link to the inventory set,
The inventory set.
It is a set which is linking
to a trait and has in touch trait,
and you can see here
that it appears the inventory set I added.
And if I click here, I can see
that these two two are connected.
An inventory could maybe also point to itself
to inventory itself, so I wanna edit the schema here
And I wanna add the inventory
that's referencing itself.
So this linking to a type to inventory itself.
And I updated, and as you can see here in the definition,
it's linking to itself.
This is the first to go.
Now I want to use a template,
which I can access over here, the template schema library.
I can also exodus over the schema
template library over here.
First, I want to add an entity, which is subtype
inside the entity.
I want to add a type to then be able to add a person
because a person can have a certain inventory.
After I edit all of these templates. I can also have a look.
After adding each one, I can go back to the model
and I can see entity here, which is nested
to an agent and then to a person.
If I have a look on the definition here, I can see
that a person has a manager also, which is linked to itself
and is part of an agent and an entity.
Since a person can have an inventory, I wanna
add a link to the inventory as well.
So I'm editing the schema
and I'm adding the property inventory.
I make it optional. I link to a type
and I link to the inventory.
And I can see here in the definition
that's now linked to the inventory.
If I want to have a look at the inventory set as well,
I can go and select these,
add them to the ontology view,
and here I can see the class diagram.
If you don't see the class diagram directly,
you can switch here from the ontology diagram
to the class diagram.
This is how you can add types traits, use templates.